<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
      <title>Photon Orbits and the Geometry of Black Holes</title>
      <link>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz</link>
      <description>Last 10 notes on Photon Orbits and the Geometry of Black Holes</description>
      <generator>Quartz -- quartz.jzhao.xyz</generator>
      <item>
    <title>Blog Post 7 - The Lyapunov Exponent</title>
    <link>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/blog7</link>
    <guid>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/blog7</guid>
    <description>Welcome back to another blog post! In this post, I’m going to finish reviewing the derivation presented in the Staelens thesis we have been following for the Lyapunov exponent, and ...</description>
    <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 01:47:32 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Blog Post 6 - Nearly Bound Orbits</title>
    <link>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/blog6</link>
    <guid>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/blog6</guid>
    <description>In the previous blog post, we established the definition of the Lyapunov in terms of the deviations of a nearly bound geodesic from its bound orbit; namely, that γ=n1​ln(δr0​δrn​​) ...</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 05:52:49 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Blog Post 5 - The Kerr-Newman Metric</title>
    <link>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/blog5</link>
    <guid>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/blog5</guid>
    <description>Welcome back to the blog! In the last post, I promised that we would finally get to the calculation of the critical exponents. Before introducing the critical exponents, however, I think it’s important to go over the actual metric that we will be calculating all of our critical exponents within.</description>
    <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 08:17:10 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Blog Post 4 - Autocorrelations and Critical Exponents</title>
    <link>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/blog4</link>
    <guid>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/blog4</guid>
    <description>You may have noticed there’s been a bit of a break in the blog! I was out of town for a while and not updating the blog super regularly, but rest assured that over the next few days I’ll be ...</description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 10:42:47 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Blog Post 0 - Introduction</title>
    <link>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/</link>
    <guid>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/</guid>
    <description>Welcome! Welcome to my blog! Over the coming weeks, I’ll be using this blog to walk through my senior project about black holes and photon rings step-by-step ...</description>
    <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 05:00:30 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Blog Post 3 - An Exercise in Geodesics</title>
    <link>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/blog3</link>
    <guid>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/blog3</guid>
    <description>Welcome to my next blog post! I’ve been promising for a few weeks now to get into the details of the geodesic equation, which governs how objects move through curved spacetime, so let’s ...</description>
    <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Blog Post 2 - Geodesics</title>
    <link>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/blog2</link>
    <guid>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/blog2</guid>
    <description>Welcome back! This week, we’ll be continuing where we left off and talking about my reading on one of the most crucial concepts in general relativity: geodesics ...</description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 09:56:32 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Blog Post 1 - General Relativity</title>
    <link>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/blog1</link>
    <guid>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/blog1</guid>
    <description>Hey everyone! Thanks for tuning into this next blog post; it’s a pretty long background one, so buckle up! In this first post after the introduction, I’m going to go through a lot of the ...</description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 02:41:51 GMT</pubDate>
  </item>
    </channel>
  </rss>